<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Resolution of the princes, allies, &amp; confederates, which has been taken at the assembly at the Hague, in the month of February, 1691 done out of French.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A57073</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">16015353</idno>
  <idno type="VID">104761</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240874728</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R1151</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36778</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">16015353</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A57073)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 104761)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1155:31)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Resolution of the princes, allies, &amp; confederates, which has been taken at the assembly at the Hague, in the month of February, 1691 done out of French.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[3] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1691?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Renee Mayes </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Renee Mayes</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="resolutions">
            <pb facs="tcp:104761:1"/>
            <head>THE RESOLUTION OF THE PRINCES ALLIES &amp; CONFEDERATES; WHICH Has been taken in the Assembly at the <hi>Hague,</hi> in the Month of <hi>February</hi> 1691.</head>
            <p>Done out of French.</p>
            <p>SINCE We look upon the Union that is between Us, as the Work of God alone, it is but rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonable that We should make a Solemn Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>testation to him to delibrate nothing in this Assembly, but what may be very just and equitable. We there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Solemnly Protest before God, that our Inten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions are, that We will never break off this Union, nor make any Peace with <hi>Lewis</hi> XIV. 'till the fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing Articles be executed: To the Obligation of which We oblige our selves for ever.</p>
            <div n="1" type="resolution">
               <pb facs="tcp:104761:2"/>
               <head>I.</head>
               <p>'Till he has made Reparation to the Holy-See, for whatsoever he has acted against it, and 'till he has an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>null'd and made void all those Infamous Proceedings against the Holy Father <hi>Innocent</hi> XI.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="resolution">
               <head>II.</head>
               <p>'Till he has restor'd to each Party concern'd, what he has taken since the Peace of <hi>Munster,</hi> and 'till he has demolish'd <hi>Brisac,</hi> and deliver'd up the Country of <hi>Geay</hi> to the Canton of <hi>Bearn.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="resolution">
               <head>III.</head>
               <p>'Till he has restor'd to the Protestants all their Goods and Possessions, and 'till there be an entire Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty of Conscience, throghout the whole extent of the <hi>French</hi> Dominions.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="resolution">
               <head>IV.</head>
               <p>'Till the Estates of the Kingdom be re-establish'd in their Ancient Liberties; so that the Clergy, the No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility, and the third Estate may enjoy their Ancient and Lawful Priviledges; And 'till the Kings for the fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture shall be oblig'd to call together the said Estates, when they desire any supply, without the Consent of Whom, they shall not raise any Mony after any man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, or for any pretence whatsoever.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="resolution">
               <head>V.</head>
               <p>'Till the Tax upon Salt, that upon the third Estate, and an infinite number of other unreasonable Taxes and Impositions, be abolish'd for ever.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="resolution">
               <head>VI.</head>
               <p>'Till he has restored to the Parliaments their Ancient and Rightful Authority; that so they may be enabled to distribute to every one Justice freely and without re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>straint, according to their Consciences.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="resolution">
               <pb facs="tcp:104761:2"/>
               <head>VII.</head>
               <p>'Till all the Towns of the Kingdom be re-establish'd in their Ancient Priviledges, and 'till their Revenues be restored, which have been taken from them with such violence and Injustice.</p>
               <p>God who knows the Intention of our Hearts, knows that We bear no Hatred against the <hi>French</hi> Nation, and that We do not aspire to have the Lawful Dominions of the Kingdom of <hi>France:</hi> And if all those who are Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants thereof would joyn with Us, We should soon dispatch this Affair without effusion of Blood, and without desolation of the Kingdom. And We promise all those that shall do it, that We will treat them as our particular Friends, and preserve their Towns and Possessions, as if they were our own: And as for those that shall not do it, We shall look upon them as Persons that have approv'd and abetted all these Persecution, Burnings and other Devastations that have been made, and We will make them feel without mercy those Pains and Torments, which they have been the occasion that so many poor People have suffer'd.</p>
               <p>We were willing that the whole World should have a perfect knowledge of our Resolutions, particularly the French Gentlemen and Persons of Honour, who are oppres't with the heavy load of the Government, and can no longer endure the Slavery which they lye under: To the end they may be able to take such Measures as may be assisting to Us, in recovering for them their Ancient Liberty which has been so cruelly, and so un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>justly taken from them.</p>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>